A Register of the William E. Ratliff papers
Hoover Institution Archives
William E. Ratliff papers
1942-2012
88023
Hoover Institution Archives
59 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 card file box. (25.8 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, sound recordings of interviews, reports, memoranda, legal proceedings, internal bulletins, opinion polls, printed matter, and photographs, relating to communism in Latin America; political and economic conditions, and especially laissez-faire economics, in Argentina, elsewhere in Latin America, and Hong Kong; President José Figueres Ferrer of Costa Rica; and the Socialist Workers Party of the United States and Trotskyist groups in Latin America.
Ratliff, William E.
Access
The collection is open for research. Sound recordings may not be duplicated. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1988, with numerous increments added on a regular basis.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biography Note
1937 Born, Evanston, Illinois
1959 Bachelor of Arts, Oberlin College
1968 Master of Arts, University of Washington
1969-Present Research Fellow, Hoover Institution
1974 Ph.D. in Latin American and Chinese history, University of Washington
1976 Author, Castroism and Communism in Latin America
1986-Present Latin American Curator, Hoover Institution Library and Archives
1986 Author, Follow the Leader in the Horn: Cuban-Soviet Presence in East Africa
1990 Author, Changing Course: The Capitalist Revolution in Argentina (with Roger W. Fontaine)
1993 Author, The Civil War in Nicaragua: Inside the Sandinistas (with Roger Miranda)
2000 Author, Law and Economics in Developing Countries (with Edgardo Buscaglia) Author, A Strategic Flip-Flop in the Caribbean (with Roger Fontaine)
2001 Author, War and Lack of Governance in Colombia: Narcos, Guerrillas, and U.S. Policy (with Edgardo Buscaglia) Author, Report from Havana: Time for a Reality Check on U.S. Policy toward Cuba (with Jonathan Clarke)
2003 Author, Doing It Wrong and Doing It Right: Education in Latin America and Asia Author, Russian Oil in America's Future
2004 Author, China's "Lessons" for Cuba's Transition?
Scope and Content of Collection
Acquired in 1988, with numerous increments added on a regular basis since then, the William E. Ratliff collection in the Hoover Institution Archives consists largely of primary source materials relating to Latin American history, with some additional materials concerning the transfer of Hong Kong to Chinese rule. There is also a considerable amount of printed matter in the collection relating to Trotskyism in Latin America and elsewhere.
As the Latin American curator of the Hoover Library and Archives, and as a scholar in the field of Latin American studies, Ratliff has made frequent research trips to Central and South America, as well as to Cuba, and has written extensively on topics pertaining to political and social developments in Latin America. He went to El Salvador in 1984 to monitor that country's elections and later wrote several analyses of this event. A number of Ratliff's many published articles are contained in the Speeches and Writings series of the collection.
A major component of the collection is the extensive series of interviews conducted by Ratliff with prominent political figures from Argentina, Chile, Costa Rica, Cuba, and Nicaragua, as well as with former officials from the United States and ex-Soviet Union with experience in Latin American affairs. A related group of interviews comprises an oral history of Costa Rican politics during the presidency of José Figueres. Other interviews cover such subjects as the civil war in El Salvador; conflict within Nicaragua during the period of the Sandinista government; views on Cuba from defectors from the Castro regime; and developments in Argentina following the end of military rule in the 1980s.
A subject of particular interest to Ratliff has been the question of market liberalization in Latin America during recent decades, and there are a number of interviews with economists and officials from the region on this subject. A smaller part of the Interviews series consists of interviews with officials in Hong Kong regarding the transfer of sovereignty in the former crown colony to China.
During the early 1980s, Ratliff was called as an expert witness in a trial involving a lawsuit brought by the Socialist Workers Party against the United States government, which was eventually found liable for damages inflicted during its surveillance of the Trotskyist SWP. Ratliff gave testimony on behalf of the government, giving his opinion on the relation, if any, between Latin American Trotskyism and terrorism. The Socialist Workers Trial File in the collection contains some transcripts of proceedings in the lawsuit, and an extensive amount of articles, pamphlets, and serial issues relating to Trotskyist groups in Latin America and elsewhere.
An early research focus of Ratliff's was the question of Chinese communist influence on leftist movements in Latin America during the 1960s. The British Foreign Office File in the collection contains a large number of articles on this subject. These excerpts from small circulation newsletters on Latin American politics are arranged by country.
Arrangement
[The collection is organized into nine series: Correspondence, Speeches and Writings, Sound Recordings of Interviews, Research Materials, Socialist Workers Party Trial File, British Foreign Office File, United States Information Agency File, Subject File, and Audiovisual File.
Figueres Ferrer, José, 1906-1990; Argentina--Economic conditions--1983-; Argentina--Politics and government--1983-2002.; Communism--Latin America.; Communism--United States.; Costa Rica--Politics and government.; Fourth International.; Hong Kong (China); Internal security--United States.; Laissez-faire.; Latin America--Economic conditions--1982-; Petroleum industry and trade--Argentina.; Phonotapes.; Public opinion--Argentina.; Socialist Workers Party.; Subversive activities--United States.; Terrorism.
- Correspondence, 1961-1970. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Letters and enclosures, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - Paton, Alan, 1966 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Ravines, Eudocio, 1970 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Russell, Bertrand, 1966 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Strout, Richard L., 1963 (Folder 1: 4)
  - White, Theodore H., 1961 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Wu, K. C., 1963 (Folder 1: 6)
- Speeches and Writings, 1966-2000.
  Articles, correspondence, interviews, reports, and speech, arranged chronologically
  - "A New Old Che Guevara Interview," The Hispanic American Historical Review, 1966 August. (Folder 1: 7)
    Printed copy. Folder includes related correspondence with Antonio de la Carrera, Theodore Draper, Rollie E. Poppino, Richard L. Walker, and Li Yu-Wan, 1960-1967
  - "The Hobbit and the Hippie," Modern Age, 1968 Spring. (Folder 1: 8)
    Printed copy. Folder includes related correspondence with J. R. R. Tolkien, 1966-1967
  - History of the Cuban labor movement and Cuban communism (with George Volsky), ca. 1984. (Folder 1: 9)
    Typescript
  - "1984 El Salvador Election Project: Background and Outlook Report" (with William Perry), Center for Strategic and International Studies, Georgetown University (Folder 1: 10)
    Printed copy. Also includes typewritten and holograph summaries of interviews conducted with Salvadoran and American officials in relation to El Salvador election
  - "The Inter-Election Period and Run-Off Outlook" (with William Perry), CSIS Latin American Election Studies Series: The Salvadoran Presidential Elections, Report No. 3, Center for Strategic and International Studies, Georgetown University, 1984 April 27. (Folder 1: 11)
    Printed copy
  - "Critics of Panama's Dictator Must Stop Shooting from Hip," The Wall Street Journal, 1987 November 6. (Folder 1: 12)
    Printed copy. Folder includes printed copy of editorial from La República (Panama) commenting on Ratliff's article, 1987 November 15
  - "The FMLN Double Standard in Human Rights," opening remarks of a debate with Oscar Orellano, Stanford University, 1989 May 5. (Folder 1: 13)
  - "Pre-Election Report," CSIS Latin American Study Series: The 1989 Chilean Elections, Center for Strategic and International Studies, Georgetown University, 1989 December 8. (Folder 1: 14)
  - "What's to Be Done in Panama?" (with Fred F. Woerner), The Miami Herald, 1989 December 24. (Folder 1: 15)
  - "Asylum, in the Drug Lords' Gun Sights, May Be the Best Medicine" (with Fred F. Woerner), Los Angeles Times, 1989 December 27. (Folder 1: 16)
  - "Several Steps Remain for the U.S. to take in Panama" (with Fred F. Woerner), Chicago Tribune, 1989 December 27. (Folder 1: 17)
  - "Yanqui Don't Go Home--Yet," Los Angeles Times, 1990 January (?). (Folder 1: 18)
  - "The Electoral Transition to Democratic Rule," CSIS Latin American Election Study Series: The 1989 Chilean Elections, Center for Strategic and International Studies, Georgetown University, 1990 January 16. (Folder 1: 19)
  - "The Inauguration and Looking toward the Future," CSIS Latin American Election Study Series: The 1989 Chilean Elections, Center for Strategic and International Studies, Georgetown University, 1990 April 25. (Folder 1: 20)
  - Interview conducted by William Ratliff with Domingo Cavallo, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1993 August 9. (Folder 1: 21)
  - Interview conducted by William Ratliff and Timothy Brown with Alberto Fujimori, Lima, Peru, 1996 June 28. (Folder 1: 22)
    Typescript summary
  - "Development and Governance in Latin America,", 1998. (Folder 1: 23)
    Typescript of a series of short interviews with Harald Beyer, Enrique Cardenas Sanchez, Hernando De Soto, and an anonymous Mexican official
  - Interview conducted by William Ratliff with Lawrence Harrison, 1998 March 10. (Folder 1: 24)
  - Interview conducted by William Ratliff with anonymous former official in the Argentine Economy Ministry, 1998 March 13. (Folder 1: 25)
  - Interview conducted by William Ratliff with anonymous former Argentine ministerial official, 1998 March 16. (Folder 1: 26)
  - "National Bipartisan Commission on Cuba - 1998,", 1998 October 19. (Folder 1: 27)
    Typescript of a series of short interviews with Lawrence Eagleburger, Roger Fontaine, and William D. Rogers
  - "The Panama Canal: An Online NewsHour Special Report," PBS, 1999 December. (Folder 1: 28)
    Transcript of online interview with William E. Ratliff and John J. Tierney
  - Interview conducted by William Ratliff, Scott Hogenson, and R. Emmett Tyrell with Nursultan Nazarbayev, Astana, Kazakhstan, 2000 March 21. (Folder 1: 29)
    Typescript summary (in English) of interview, and typescript of written answers (in Russian) provided by Nazarbayev
- Sound Recordings of Interviews, 1992-1999. (Box 2)
  Compact and mini sound cassettes with recorded interviews, arranged chronologically by subject, thereunder chronologically by name of interviewee
  - Costa Rica, 1992.
    Interviews conducted in San José, Costa Rica, as part of an oral history of Costa Rican politics and, in particular, the administration of José (Pepe) Figueres
    - Jorge Manuel Dengo and Jorge Rossi, 1992 January 27. (Folder 2: 1)
      One compact sound cassette
    - Uladislao Gá mez, 1992 January 27. (Folder 2: 2)
    - Padre Benjamín Nuñez, 1992 January 27. (Folder 2: 3)
    - Max Cortés, 1992 January 28. (Folder 2: 4-5)
      Two compact sound cassettes
    - Gastó n Kogan, 1992 January 28. (Folder 2: 6)
    - Jorge Manuel Dengo and Jorge Rossi (second interview), 1992 January 29. (Folder 2: 7-8)
    - Luis Alberto Monje (name on label is misidentified as Monge-Lamarge), 1992 January 29. (Folder 2: 9)
    - Alberto Cañas, 1992 January 30. (Folder 2: 10)
    - José Joaquín Trejos Ferná ndez, 1992 January 30. (Folder 2: 11)
    - Carlos Vicente, 1992 January 30. (Folder 2: 12)
    - Herná n Garró n, 1992 January 31 (Folder 2: 13)
      (name on label is misidentified as Garrou). One compact sound cassette
    - Rufino Gil Pacheco (name on one label is misidentified as G.4 Pochivo), 1992 February 3. (Folder 2: 14-15)
    - Guillermo Villegas Hoffmaister, 1992 February 3. (Folder 2: 16-17)
    - Rodrigo Fournier (name on one label is misidentified as Rodriy Founnier), 1992 February 4. (Folder 2: 18)
    - Manuel Mora Valverde, 1992 February 5. (Folder 2: 19-20)
    - Nini Chinchilla de Mora, 1992 February 6. (Folder 2: 21)
    - Fernando Naranjo, 1992 February 6. (Folder 2: 22)
    - José Gutiérrez Gó ngora, 1992 November. (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
    - José Maria Figueres, 1992 November. (Folder 3: 3)
    - Luis Alberto Monje (second interview), 1992 November. (Folder 3: 4)
    - Oscar Arias, 1992 November. (Folder 3: 5)
  - Nicaragua, 1992-1993
    - Brooklyn Rivera, unknown location, 1992 October. (Folder 3: 6)
    - Alfonso Robelo, unknown location, 1992 November. (Folder 3: 7)
    - Antonio Ybarra Rojas, Cochabamba, Bolivia, 1993 March 14-18. (Folder 3: 8-15)
      Eight compact sound cassettes
    - Moises Hassan, lecture and interview, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, 1993. (Folder 3: 16-18)
      Three compact sound cassettes
  - Market liberalization in Latin America, 1992-1993
    (interviews unless otherwise indicated)
    - Emetério Gó mez, CEDICE conference, Caracas Venezuela, 1992 November 16. (Folder 3: 19)
    - Salvador á vila, Caracas, Venezuela, 1992 November 17. (Folder 3: 20)
    - Arturo Salazar, Guayaquil, Ecuador, 1992 November 19. (Folder 3: 21)
    - Martin Krause, Guayaquil, Ecuador, 1992 November 20. (Folder 3: 22-23)
    - Staci Sticht, International Republican Institute, Washington, D.C., 1993 January 6. (Folder 3: 24)
  - Cuba, 1993
    - Mario Chanes and Ernesto Diaz, San Francisco, California, 1993 October 3. (Folder 3: 25-26)
    - Juan Antonio Rodriquez Menier, United States (undisclosed location), 1993 October 5. (Folder 3: 27)
  - Argentina, 1993-1996. (Box 4)
    Interviews conducted in Buenos Aires unless otherwise noted
    - Luis Calviño and Julio César Ará oz, 1993 February 24-March 5. (Folder 4: 1)
    - Alberto Massa and Mario Kamelman Levitin, 1993 March 1. (Folder 4: 2)
    - Mario Kamelman Levitin (part two), 1993 March 1. (Folder 4: 3)
    - Juan Manuel Cassella and Alfredo Olivera, 1993 March 3. (Folder 4: 4)
    - Juan Manuel Cassella (part two), 1993 March 3-4. (Folder 4: 5)
    - Enrique Tanoni, Salta, Argentina, 1993 March 6. (Folder 4: 6-7)
    - Richard Boucher and Luis Calviño (second interview), 1993 March 7. (Folder 4: 8)
    - Peter Whitney, 1993 March 8. (Folder 4: 9)
    - Palo Carlos Rojo, 1993 July 26. (Folder 4: 10)
    - Jose Luis Tagliaferri, 1993 July 26. (Folder 4: 11-12)
    - Antonio Cafiero, 1993 August 6. (Folder 4: 13)
    - Domingo Cavallo, 1993 August 9. (Folder 4: 14)
    - Martin Oyuela, 1993 August 9. (Folder 4: 15)
    - Hugo Haime, 1993 August 10. (Folder 4: 16)
    - Manuel Mora, 1993 August 11. (Folder 4: 17)
    - Mario Bronemberg, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, 1993 October 12-19. (Folder 4: 18-19)
  - U.S. Policy in Central America, 1993. (Folder 4: 20-24)
    Interviews with Roger Fontaine, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1993 March 2-8. Five compact sound cassettes
  - Central America and Chile, 1994. (Folder 4: 25-26)
    Interview with John Biehl, 1994. Two mini sound cassettes
  - Peru, 1994. (Folder 4: 27-31)
    Interviews with Fernando Belaúnde Terry, Stanford University, 1994 April 4-6. Five compact sound cassettes
  - Argentina, 1996-1997. (Box 5)
    - Manuel Mora (second interview), 1996 April 22. (Folder 5: 1)
    - Luis Calviño (second interview), 1996 April 27. (Folder 5: 2-3)
    - Martin Krause (second interview), 1996 April 29. (Folder 5: 4)
    - Domingo Cavallo, Healdsburg, California, 1996 May 5. (Folder 5: 5-7)
      Includes some comments by Milton Friedman. Three compact sound cassettes
    - Jose Octavio Bordon, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, 1997 May 9. (Folder 5: 8-9)
  - Latin America and the Soviet Union, 1996-1997. (Folder 5: 10-27)
    Interviews with Oleg Daroussenkov, Healdsburg and Stanford, California, 1996 December 7 - 1997 April 12. Eighteen compact sound cassettes (thirteen cassettes are mislabeled as Darousseykov)
  - Latin America and the United States, 1997-1999
    - P. Peter Sarros, location unknown, 1997-1999. (Folder 5: 28-33)
      Five compact sound cassettes
    - Lawrence Harrison, location unknown, 1998 January 6-15. (Box-folder 6: 1-8)
  - Bulgaria, 1997. Interview with King Simeon II, Madrid, Spain, 1997 December 11. (Folder 6: 9)
  - Hong Kong, 1997.
    Interviews conducted in Hong Kong
    - Francis Lui, 1997 July. (Folder 6: 10-17)
    - Chi His-sheng, 1997 July 2. (Folder 6: 18-19)
    - Law Chi Kwong, 1997 July 2. (Folder 6: 20-22)
    - Allen Lee Peng-fei, 1997 September 22. (Folder 6: 23)
    - Martin Lee, 1997 September 23. (Folder 6: 24)
- Research Materials, 1984-1990. (Box 7)
  Article, clippings, interview, leaflets and sticker, press releases, reports, serial issues, speech, and surveys used in the preparation of Changing Course: The Capitalist Revolution in Argentina, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Article, Floria, Carlos, "La turbulenta transició n de la Argentina secreta," (Folder 7: 1)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Folder 7: 2-3)
  - Interview conducted by William Ratliff and Roger W. Fontaine with Raul Alfonsin, 1990 May. (Folder 7: 4)
  - Leaflets and sticker, 1990 (Folder 7: 5)
  - Press releases issued by the foreign ministry of Argentina, 1989-1990. (Folder 7: 6-7)
    Consists of transcripts of interviews and press conferences given by foreign minister Domingo Cavallo
  - Reports.
    Typescript drafts and printed copies
    - 1989-1990 (Folder 7: 8)
    - 1993 (Folder 7: 9-11)
  - Serial issues, 1990. (Folder 7: 12)
    Printed copies
  - Speech by Julio César Ará oz, Latin American Energy Forum, Houston, Texas, 1990 June 27. (Folder 7: 13)
  - Surveys, 1990. (Box 8)
    Results of opinion polls conducted in Argentina, listed by polling firm
    - Aftalió n Mora y Araujo Noguera y Asociados
      - 1984 (Folder 8: 1-3)
      - 1985 (Folder 8: 4-5)
      - 1986 (Folder 8: 6-7)
      - 1987 (Folder 8: 8-9)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
      - 1988 (Folder 9: 3-10)
      - 1989 (Folder 9: 11-12)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 10: 1-12)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 11: 1-6)
      - 1990 (Folder 11: 7-12)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 12: 1-2)
      - 1993 (Folder 12: 3-7)
    - Hugo Haime y Asociados, 1993 (Folder 12: 8)
    - Muraro y Asociados (Box 13)
      - 1992 (Folder 13: 1)
      - 1993 (Folder 13: 2-9)
    - Telecom S. A., 1990 (Folder 13: 10)
- Socialist Workers Party Trial File, 1949-1981. (Box 14)
  Background materials, clippings, correspondence, and trial documents relating to a lawsuit brought by the Socialist Workers Party against the U.S. government, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Background materials used by William Ratliff in preparation for his testimony, 1949-1981
    - Declassified Central Intelligence Agency reports and cables, 1949-1976
      - Fourth International, 1949-1975 (Folder 14: 1-2)
      - Trotskyism in Latin America
        - General, 1965-1974 (Folder 14: 3)
        - Argentina, 1967-1976 (Folder 14: 4)
        - Bolivia, 1961-1971 (Folder 14: 5)
        - Brazil, 1967 (Folder 14: 6)
        - Cuba, 1961 (Folder 14: 7)
        - Mexico, 1964-1972 (Folder 14: 8)
        - Peru, 1962-1972 (Folder 14: 9)
        - Uruguay, 1965-1970 (Folder 14: 10)
    - Notes and draft of question, 1981 (Folder 14: 11)
    - Printed matter, 1960-1981. (Folder 14: 12-13, Box-folder 15: 1-9, Box-folder 17: 1-8)
      Clippings, monograph excerpts, and serial issues relating to international Trotskyism, especially Trotskyism in Latin America. Includes some photocopies of miscellaneous correspondence relating to Trotskyist organizations
  - Clippings, 1981 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1981
    - Unidentified, 1981 (Folder 18: 2)
    - Auerswald, Steve, 1981 (Folder 18: 3)
  - Trial documents, 1981
    - Affidavits, 1981 (Folder 18: 4)
    - Digests of testimony, 1981
      - George Baxtrum (Folder 18: 5)
      - William Ratliff (Folder 18: 6)
    - Transcripts of proceedings, 1981 (Folder 18: 7)
    - Post-trial memoranda, 1981 (Folder 18: 8-9)
    - Judge's opinion, 1981 (Folder 18: 10)
- British Foreign Office File, 1962-1971. (Box 19)
  Newsletters arranged alphabetically by title, and clippings arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Newsletters
    - Communism and Latin America
      - 1967
        - January-March (Folder 19: 1)
        - April-June (Folder 19: 2)
        - July-August (Folder 19: 3)
        - September (Folder 19: 4)
        - October (Folder 19: 5)
        - November-December (Folder 19: 6)
      - 1968
        - January-February (Folder 19: 7)
        - March-April (Folder 19: 8)
        - May-June (Folder 19: 9)
        - July-August (Folder 19: 10)
        - September-October (Box-folder 20: 1)
        - November-December (Folder 20: 2)
    - Latin America Notes
      - 1968
        - January 4 - March 28 (Folder 20: 3)
        - April 4 - June 27 (Folder 20: 4)
        - July 11 - September 26 (Folder 20: 5)
      - 1969
        - April 24 - June 26 (Folder 20: 6)
        - July 10 - September 25 (Folder 20: 8)
        - October 2 - December 18 (Folder 20: 9)
      - 1970
        - January 1 - June 25 (Folder 20: 10)
        - July 2 - December 17 (Folder 20: 11)
      - 1971 (Box 21)
        - January 7 - March 25 (Folder 21: 1)
        - April 1 - June 24 (Folder 21: 2)
        - July 1 - September 30 (Folder 21: 3)
        - October 19 - December 21 (Folder 21: 4)
    - Latin American Topics
      - 1969
        - April-June (Folder 21: 5)
        - July-December (Folder 21: 6)
      - 1970
        - January-April (Folder 21: 7)
        - May-August (Folder 21: 8)
        - September-December (Folder 21: 9)
      - 1971
        - January-April (Folder 21: 10)
        - May-July (Box-folder 22: 1)
        - September-December (Folder 22: 2)
  - Subject file, 1962-1968.
    Excerpts from newsletters, as organized by William Ratliff
    - Chinese communist influence in Latin America.
      Includes materials on the Sino-Soviet split and its effects on Latin American politics, especially in relation to Cuba and communist organizations
      - General
        - 1962-1963 (Folder 22: 3)
        - 1964 (Folder 22: 4)
        - 1965 (Folder 22: 5)
        - 1966-1968 (Folder 22: 6)
      - Argentina, 1963-1967 (Folder 22: 7)
      - Bolivia, 1963-1967 (Folder 22: 8)
      - Brazil, 1963-1967 (Folder 22: 9)
      - Chile, 1963-1967 (Folder 22: 10)
      - Colombia, 1963-1968 (Folder 22: 11)
      - Costa Rica, 1963-1968 (Folder 22: 12)
      - Ecuador, 1962-1968 (Folder 22: 13)
      - Guatemala, 1966-1967 (Folder 22: 14)
      - Mexico, 1963-1967 (Folder 22: 15)
      - Panama, 1964-1967 (Folder 22: 16)
      - Peru, 1963-1968 (Folder 22: 17)
      - Uruguay, 1963-1968 (Folder 22: 18)
      - Venezuela, 1964-1966 (Folder 22: 19)
    - Cuba—Politics and government (Box 23)
      - 1967 (Folder 23: 1)
      - 1968 (Folder 23: 2)
- United States Information Agency File, 1956-1970.